子供たち[こどもたち]:children, 大黒[だいこく]:god of wealth|monk's wife, 市[いち]:market/fair, 市[し]:city, 最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now
（ヤサコ）
子供たちのウワサによると
大黒市(だいこくし)では 最近―
According to rumors among the other kids,
many cases of pets going missing
ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET, 行方不明[ゆくえふめい]:missing/unaccounted for, 事件[じけん]:event/affair/incident, 多発[たはつ]:repeated occurrence
ペットの行方不明事件が
多発しているそうです
have been occurring in Daikoku City recently.
（ヤサコ）あっ あれは…
What's that?
（京子(きょうこ)）んっ？
霧[きり]:fog/mist|spray, お姉ちゃん[おねえちゃん]:familiar form of "older sister"|form of address for young adult female
霧だ！　お姉ちゃん 霧があるよ
Fog!
It's fog, Yuko!
空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 壊れる[こわれる]:to be broken/to break|to fall through, 霧[きり]:fog/mist|spray
（ヤサコ）あれは
空間が壊れたときに出る霧だわ
That's the fog that comes out whenever a Space breaks.
引っ越す[ひっこす, ひきこす]:to move (house)/to change residence, 早々[そうそう]:as soon as.../just after...|hurriedly, 早々[はやはや]:quickly, 幸先[さいさき]:omen/sign (usually good), 悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
なんか引っ越し早々
幸先 悪いわね
It's kind of a bad omen, just now since we're moving.
大黒[だいこく]:god of wealth|monk's wife
（アナウンス）
まもなく 大黒 大黒です
We'll be arriving at Daikoku shortly. Daikoku.
いっけ:a house/a home/a family, いっけ:prefix used to strengthen a derogatory adjective, 降りる[おりる]:to descend (e.g. a mountain)|to alight (e.g. from bus)|to step down||
いっけない！　降りるわよ
Oh no!
Let's get off!
Please make sure you don't forget any of your belongings on board.
We'll be arriving at Daikoku shortly. Daikoku.
はい 京子
（京子）えっ？
Here, Kyoko!
はい デンスケ
Here you go, Densuke!
（デンスケ）ワオ～ン！
ク～ン…
急ぐ[いそぐ]:to hurry/to rush/to hasten
ほら 京子 急ぐわよ
Come on, Kyoko, let's hurry!
（イサコ）来た
It's here.
猫[ねこ, ネコ]:cat|shamisen|geisha||, 猫[ねこま]:cat, 入れる[いれる]:to put in|to admit|to accept||
そうだ そのまま猫の中に入れ
Come on...
Just enter the cat.
クソッ あとちょっとだったのに…
Crap! I was so close...
チェッ
お母さん[おかあさん]:mother
（ヤサコ）
あっ お母さん？
Mom...
大黒[だいこく]:god of wealth|monk's wife, 駅[えき]:station
今 大黒駅にいる
なんで来てないの？
We're at Daikoku Station now.
The Kids with Glasses
Why aren't you here yet?
（静江(しずえ)）ごめん ごめん
Sorry, sorry.
引っ越し[ひっこし]:moving (dwelling, office, etc.)/changing residence, 屋[や]:(something) shop|somebody who sells (something) or works as (something)|somebody with a (certain) personality trait||, 道[みち]:road|distance|the way (of proper conduct, etc.)||, 道[どう]:road|way|Buddhist teachings||, 間違える[まちがえる]:to make a mistake (in)/to commit an error (e.g. in calculation)|to confuse
引っ越し屋さんが
道 間違えちゃって
The company driver took a wrong turn.
道[みち]:road|distance|the way (of proper conduct, etc.)||, 道[どう]:road|way|Buddhist teachings||
来たことあるんだし
道 分かるでしょ？
You've been here before, so you know the way home, right?
先[さき]:previous|point (e.g. pencil)|head (of a line)||, 先[せん]:former/previous|first move (in go, shogi, etc.)
おばあちゃん待ってるから
先 行ってて
Granny is waiting for you, so go on ahead.
（ヤサコ）えっ？　でも…
Eh? But...
タクシー:taxi
タクシー？
A taxi...
んにゅ！
ハハ～ エヘヘッ
しかたない:it can't be helped/it's inevitable/it's no use
もう… しかたないな
Well, if we really have to...
苦手[にがて]:poor (at)/weak (in)|dislike (of)
ハァ… ヤダな
おばば 苦手なのよね
Geez...
I don't even get along well with Granny.
タクシー:taxi, 全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely
そのタクシーも
全然 来ないじゃない
There's not a taxi in sight yet...
ウンチ！
Poop!
やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit, 恥ずかしい[はずかしい]:shy/ashamed|disgraceful
そのウンチって言うのやめてよ
恥ずかしいわね
Stop saying "poop"!
It's so embarrassing!
何かやって！
デンスケで何かやって！
Do something! Tell Densuke to do something!
何かって… そうねえ
Something?
Let me see...
転[くるり]:turning around (once)|suddenly|completely (wrapped in something)||, 転[てん]:altering pronunciation or meaning/word with altered pronunciation or meaning|turning or twisting part of a text (in Chinese poetry)
じゃあ デンスケ バク転
Okay, Densuke.
Back handspring!
ウンチ！
Poop!
なさる:to do
きょ… 京子 待ちなさい！
K-Kyoko!
Wait up!
I... I'm sorry!—
ど… どうもすみませんでした
京子！　どこ行ったの？
待ってろって言ったのに
Kyoko!
I said to wait up! Where did you get off to?
京子！
Kyoko!
勝手に[かってに]:arbitrarily/of its own accord/voluntarily, 動く[うごく]:to move|to operate|to be touched||
もう 勝手に動かないでよ
You can't just do as you please!
ウンチ！
Poop!
かしら:I wonder, かしら:head|hair (on one's head)
（ヤサコ）これ 何かしら？
I wonder what that is.
まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected, 本物[ほんもの]:genuine article/real thing/real deal
まさか本物のウン…
I can't believe it's real poo—
電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 物質[ぶっしつ]:material/substance|matter
よかった 電脳物質ね
Oh, it's okay.
It's a cybersubstance.
続く[つづく]:to continue|to continue (without a break)|to occur again and again||
あっ 続いてるよ
There's more over there.
デッカいウンチ！
A huge poop!
一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||
一体なんなのよ？　これは
What is this thing?
蒸発[じょうはつ]:evaporation|disappearance (of people intentionally concealing their whereabouts)/unexplained disappearance
蒸発していくわ
Is it evaporating?
ヘルプ:help
デンスケ ヘルプある？
Densuke, is there a help file?
Help not Found
（デンスケ）アウ～ウ
ヘルプ:help, 違法[いほう]:illegal/illegality/invalid, 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 物質[ぶっしつ]:material/substance|matter, かしら:I wonder, かしら:head|hair (on one's head)
ヘルプもないの？
違法の電脳物質かしら？
So there isn't...
Could it be an illegal cybersubstance?
ハッ！　ヒヒャハハ～
なさる:to do
ま… 待ちなさい！
W-Wait!
電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 猫[ねこ, ネコ]:cat|shamisen|geisha||, 猫[ねこま]:cat
（フミエ）
おっ いたいた！　電脳猫だわ
There it is! It's a cybercat!
名前は…
Its name is...
変[へん]:strange|unexpected|change||
ヘップバーン？　変な名前ね
Hepburn?
What a weird name.
猫[ねこ, ネコ]:cat|shamisen|geisha||, 猫[ねこま]:cat
（ダイチ）
うりゃ～！　待て この猫が！
Hey!
Hold it right there, cat!
獲物[えもの]:game/spoils/trophy
ちょっと！　私の獲物に何すんの！
Hey!
What are you doing to my quarry?!
あっ フミエ
Oh. Fumie.
先[さき]:previous|point (e.g. pencil)|head (of a line)||, 先[せん]:former/previous|first move (in go, shogi, etc.), 依頼[いらい]:request/commission|dependence, 受ける[うける, ウケる]:to receive|to catch (e.g. a ball)|to be struck by (wind, waves, sunlight, etc.)||
（フミエ）
私が先に依頼を受けたのよ
I was asked to capture it before you were!
商売[しょうばい]:trade/business/commerce, 始める[はじめる]:to start|to open (e.g. a store)|to start ..., 先[さき]:previous|point (e.g. pencil)|head (of a line)||, 先[せん]:former/previous|first move (in go, shogi, etc.)
商売 始めたのは俺が先だ
Yeah, but I'm the one who started the business!
（ダイチ）ヘップバーン？
（フミエ）ヘップバーン？
Hepburn...
Hepburn!
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, かしら:I wonder, かしら:head|hair (on one's head)
ホントに
どこ行っちゃったのかしら？
Just where did they run off to?
デンスケ！
Densuke!
京子！
Kyoko!
What a mess...
困る[こまる]:to be troubled/to be worried/to be bothered
困ったな
Densuke?
デンスケ？
それ！
Gotcha!
Alright!
よーし:alright/all right/right on, 捕まえる[つかまえる]:to catch/to arrest/to seize
よーし 捕まえた
I got you now.
電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 猫[ねこ, ネコ]:cat|shamisen|geisha||, 猫[ねこま]:cat
あら？　ヤダ 電脳猫
Oh, it's a cybercat.
紛らわしい[まぎらわしい]:confusing/misleading/equivocal
何よ 紛らわしい
How deceptive.
Hepburn!
（フミエ）ヘップバーン！
Hey!
ちょっと あんた誰？
Who are you?
獲物[えもの]:game/spoils/trophy
私の獲物に何すんの？
And what are you doing to my quarry?
先回り[さきまわり]:going on ahead/forestalling/anticipating, 横取り[よこどり]:usurpation/snatching/seizure, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
先回りして横取りするなんて
It's rude to grab other people's quarries just as they're...
Anyway, you must be a friend of Daichi!
さては ダイチの仲間ね
Wh-What are you...
な… 何よ
返し[かえし]:reversal|return gift|barb (on a fishing hook)|, 獲物[えもの]:game/spoils/trophy
返しな それは私の獲物よ
Give it back!
That's my quarry!
If you don't, I'll give you a hard time!
渡す[わたす]:to ferry across (e.g. a river)|to lay across|to hand over
渡さないとヒドいわよ
I-I don't know what you're talking about!
意味[いみ]:meaning/significance
い… 意味 分かんない
ダイチって何？
Who's Daichi?
素人[しろうと, しろと]:amateur|respectable woman (not a prostitute, hostess, geisha, etc.)|unlicensed prostitute
あっ なんだ… 素人さんか
Oh, so you're a noob.
Come on, hand it over!
譲る[ゆずる]:to turn over/to assign|to yield, いくら:how much?/how many?|even
ねえ 譲って
いくら？　いくらならいいの？
How much?
So how much do you want?
C'mon, I don't have all day.
ねえ 時間がないのよ
So,
ねえ これでどう？
how's this?
200 meta! More than enough, right?
相当[そうとう]:befitting|considerable|to be worthy of||
200メタ相当よ どう？
Well?
獲物[えもの]:game/spoils/trophy, 気[き]:spirit|nature|motivation||, 気[げ]:seeming/giving the appearance of/giving one the feeling of
（ダイチ）
あっ 俺の獲物 どうする気だ！
What do you think you're doing with my quarry?
H-He's here!
交換[こうかん]:exchange/interchange/switching
き… 来た
じゃあ これで交換ね
Okay, it's a deal!
Why you...!
あっ この… 待て こら！
Hey, wait!
Wait!
待て！
Cyberinvestigation
Cyberinvestigation?
電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 探偵[たんてい]:detective/sleuth/investigator
電脳探偵？
Densuke!
（ヤサコ）デンスケ！
Kyoko!
京子！
もう どこ行ったのよ
Where are they?
That's right!
位置[いち]:place/situation/position, 表示[ひょうじ]:indication|display|representation, ソフト:soft
そうだ 位置を表示する
ソフトがあったんだ
I have a tracking system.
There we go.
出た
Good, they're nearby.
近く[ちかく]:near|nearly (e.g. "it took nearly one year")|shortly
何よ すぐ近くじゃない
Densuke!
（ヤサコ）デンスケ！
That's odd...
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, 辺[へん]:area|side|circumstances, 辺[へ, べ]:surrounding area|shore (of the sea)|suffix used as a rough indicator of location, direction, time, etc.
おっかしいな
確かに この辺のはず…
It should be around here—
ガウ！　ガウ！　ガウガウ！
こ… 来ないで！
S-Stay back!
な… 何よ これ？
What is that?
I'll hit you if you come any closer!
来たら ぶつわよ！
No Data
ハァ ハァ…
D-D-D...
こ… こ… 来ないで！
Don't come any closer!
（うなり声）
（ヤサコ）デンスケ！
Densuke!
Densuke...
デンスケ…
Auto-restoring
Densuke!
デンスケ！
（デンスケ）ワン！
Oh no!
大変[たいへん]:very|immense|serious||
あっ 大変！
Restoration Complete
デンスケ
Densuke...
This is awful.
大変[たいへん]:very|immense|serious||
た… 大変　どうしよう？
What should I do?
Oh yeah...
一度[いちど, ひとたび]:once|temporarily|one degree, 穴[あな]:hole|deficit|vacancy||, 穴[けつ]:ass|rear|acupuncture point|
そうだ もう一度 穴を…
I'll do it
one more time!
ハァ… ダメだわ
It's no good.
Sis!
お姉ちゃん[おねえちゃん]:familiar form of "older sister"|form of address for young adult female
（京子）お姉ちゃん！
Kyoko.
（ヤサコ）京子
（京子）デンスケは？
Where's Densuke?
Well...
それが…
Densuke?
デンスケ？
He's not here...
いないわ
What happened to him?
（京子）ねえ どうしたの？
I can hear Densuke's barking coming from somewhere around here.
声[こえ]:voice, あちこち:here and there/all around|to get things in the wrong order (back to front), 聞こえる[きこえる]:to be heard/to be audible|to be said to be
（ヤサコ）デンスケの声が
あちこちから聞こえるの
Where is he?
どこにいるの？
Densuke!
デンスケ！
（ヤサコ）
デンスケ！　デンスケ…
Densuke!
This is the Support Center.
サポートセンター:support centre (center)
（自動音声）
サポートセンターです
All of our lines are currently busy.
回線[かいせん]:circuit/line, 大変[たいへん]:very|immense|serious||, 混み合う[こみあう]:to be crowded/to be packed/to be jammed
ただ今 回線が
大変 混み合っております
Please stay on the line, or dial again at a later time.
しばらく:little while/short while|a while, いただく:to receive/to get|to eat, 一度[いちど, ひとたび]:once|temporarily|one degree
もうしばらくお待ちいただくか
もう一度…
Please stay on the line, or dial again at a later time.
Yuko!
（静江）優子(ゆうこ)！　優子！
Yuko.
上がる[あがる]:to rise|to enter (esp. from outdoors)|to enter (a school)||
優子 上がってらっしゃい
Come upstairs.
It's a present from Grandpa.
プレゼント:present/gift
おじいちゃんのプレゼントよ
（ヤサコ）
わあー ハハ！
That poor little girl...
かわいそう:poor/pitiable/pathetic
（親戚のおばあさん）
かわいそうにねえ…
Of all things, for him to die so suddenly...
やっと:at last/at length|barely, 孫[まご]:grandchild
やっと孫が来たのに
Now that he finally had a granddaughter...
ぽっくり:girl's lacquered wooden geta|wooden footwear/clogs, ぽっくり:(dying) suddenly|(breaking) brittly/with a snap, 逝く[いく, ゆく]:to go|to proceed|to pass through||, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
よりによって こんなときに
ぽっくり逝くなんてね
To Yuko - Try putting on the glasses.
可愛い[かわいい, かわゆい]:cute|dear|cute little
わあー 可愛い！
It's so cute!
ク～ン…
ク～ン ク～ン…
わあ…
I love you!
大好き[だいすき]:loveable/very likeable/like very much
大好き！
Oh yeah!
あっ そうだ
Coil Cyberinvestigation Agency...
コイル:coil, 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 探偵[たんてい]:detective/sleuth/investigator, 局[きょく]:bureau|office (e.g. post, telephone)|affair|, 局[つぼね]:court lady|separate room in a palace (esp. for a lady) (Heian period)|room for a very low class prostitute|
“コイル 電脳探偵局”
We look for missing pets.
行方不明[ゆくえふめい]:missing/unaccounted for, ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET, 捜す[さがす]:to search (for something desired, needed)/to look for|to search (for something lost)
〝行方不明のペット
捜します 〞？
Aren't you getting in?
乗る[のる]:to get on (train, plane, bus, ship, etc.)|to get on (e.g. a footstool)|to reach||
（静江）乗らないの？
（ヤサコ）
デンスケがいなくなっちゃったの
Densuke is missing.
捜す[さがす]:to search (for something desired, needed)/to look for|to search (for something lost)
捜してくる
I'll go look for him.
（京子）えっ 京子も行く
I want to go too!
（ヤサコ）ダメ！
No way!
まだ来てないのかな？
She's not here yet?
今どき[いまどき]:these days/nowadays|at this time (of the day)
ＵＦＯ… 今どき？
A UFO?
Nowadays?
客[きゃく, かく]:guest/visitor|customer, 客[まろうど, まろうと]:visitor from afar/guest
（フミエ）お客さん
Hey boss!
（フミエ）また会ったわね
So we meet again.
静か[しずか]:quiet|slow|calm, じっと:motionlessly (e.g. stand, wait)/(be) still|fixedly (e.g. gaze, stare)
静かに… じっとして
Quiet.
Don't move.
最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, 増える[ふえる]:to increase/to multiply
最近 増えたわよね キュウちゃん
There've been a lot more Kyuu-chans lately.
キュウちゃん？
"Kyuu-chans"?
球体[きゅうたい]:sphere/globe/orb
知らないの？
球体だからキュウちゃん
You've never heard of 'em?
They're "Kyuu-chans" because they're spherical.
Kyuu means sphere.
So what's the assignment?
仕事[しごと]:work/job|work
で 仕事は何？
ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET, 壁[かべ, へき]:wall|barrier|Chinese "Wall" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)
（ヤサコ）あっ ペットが
壁の中に入っちゃったの
My pet has entered a wall.
There was a hole there,
穴[あな]:hole|deficit|vacancy||, 穴[けつ]:ass|rear|acupuncture point|, 消える[きえる]:to go out/to vanish/to disappear
穴があったんだけど
すぐに消えちゃったの
but it disappeared right after.
ふーん:hmm/well ...|roughly
ふーん…
あっ あの…
私 小此木(おこのぎ)優子っていうの
Um...
My name is Yuko Okonogi.
よろしく:well/properly|best regards
よろしく…
Nice to me—
よろしく:well/properly|best regards
私は橋本(はしもと)文恵(ふみえ)よ よろしく
I'm Fumie Hashimoto.
Nice to meet you too.
空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 古い[ふるい]:old (not person)/aged/ancient
ふむ… 空間が古いわね
This Space is so obsolete.
料金[りょうきん]:fee/charge/fare
料金は200メタだけどいい？
The price is 200 meta, okay?
メタ？　メタって何？
Meta?
What're meta?
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, 渡す[わたす]:to ferry across (e.g. a river)|to lay across|to hand over
あんた メタバグも知らないの？
ほら さっき渡した…
What? You don't even know what a meta-bug is?
Remember? It's like the one I gave you earlier.
ちょうど:exactly/precisely|as if, ちょうど:supplies/furniture/fixtures
（フミエ）そう それ
それでちょうどです
Yeah, that one!
That one will do just fine.
どんな:what/what kind of|(with -temo, demo, etc.) any(body, thing, means, etc.), 状況[じょうきょう]:state of affairs (around you)/situation/circumstances, 壁[かべ, へき]:wall|barrier|Chinese "Wall" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)
で どんな状況で壁ん中に？
So tell me more about how it went through the wall.
変[へん]:strange|unexpected|change||, 黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, 生き物[いきもの]:living thing/animal
それが変な黒い生き物に
ついていって…
Well, it was following a strange, black, living creature...
ハッ！　なんですって？
What?!
（フミエ）うん そう　そうよ
Yes.
That's right...
That's right.
She said she spotted an Illegal.
イリーガル:illegal
イリーガル見たんだってさ
うん 分かったわ メガばあ
Understood, Mega-baa.
勝手に[かってに]:arbitrarily/of its own accord/voluntarily
（ヤサコ）ねえ
ここ 勝手に入っていいの？
Is it really all right to come in like this?
霧[きり]:fog/mist|spray, 急ぐ[いそぐ]:to hurry/to rush/to hasten
霧だわ
急いだほうがよさそうね
This fog...
We'd better get moving.
取る[とる]:to take|to steal|to eat||
ちょっと それ取って
（ヤサコ）えっ？
Pick that up for a sec.
古い[ふるい]:old (not person)/aged/ancient, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, だいぶ:lengthy (of a book, etc.)/voluminous|most (e.g. most part), だいぶ:considerably/greatly/a lot, 廃棄[はいき]:disposal/abandonment|annulment
（フミエ）古い空間は だいぶ前に
廃棄されたはずの空間なの
This obsolete Space was supposed to have been abandoned some time ago.
入り込む[はいりこむ, いりこむ]:to go into/to come into|to become complicated, ヤバい:dangerous|awful|terrific
そこに入り込んだとなると
ちょっとヤバいかもね
If he's really inside,
it might be dangerous.
特に[とくに]:particularly/especially, 最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET
特に最近のペットはね
Especially for a modern pet like him.
どういう:somehow/how/in what way
（ヤサコ）どういうこと？
What do you mean?
バージョン:version, 合う[あう, おう]:to come together|to fit|to be profitable|, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET, 体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, 壊れる[こわれる]:to be broken/to break|to fall through, やすい:cheap/inexpensive|calm, やすい:easy|likely to .../have a tendency to ...
（フミエ）
バージョンが合わない空間では
ペットの体は壊れやすくなるのよ
If a pet is in a Space of a different version,
its body gets weaker.
W-Weaker?
壊れる[こわれる]:to be broken/to break|to fall through, やすい:cheap/inexpensive|calm, やすい:easy|likely to .../have a tendency to ...
壊れやすくなる？
（フミエ）すぐには死なないわ
It won't die right away.
ちょっとどいて
Step back for a sec.
認識[にんしき]:recognition/awareness/perception
認識
Scan!
Scan Complete
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, 助ける[たすける]:to save|to help|to aid|
（ヤサコ）ねえ こんなんで
ホントにデンスケ助けられるの？
Can you really save Densuke like this?
なさる:to do
まあ 見てなさいよ
Just you watch.
な… 何よ これ？
Wh-What's that?!
黒[くろ]:black|black go stone|guilt, 屋[や]:(something) shop|somebody who sells (something) or works as (something)|somebody with a (certain) personality trait||, 売る[うる]:to sell
黒バグスプレー
メガシ屋で売ってるわ
Kuro bug spray.
They sell it in Megasia.
屋[や]:(something) shop|somebody who sells (something) or works as (something)|somebody with a (certain) personality trait||, 駄菓子[だがし]:cheap sweets
（ヤサコ）メガシ屋？
（フミエ）駄菓子屋の名前よ
Megasia?
It's the name of a dagashi store.
Dagashi is a popular Japanese sweet.
No Data
穴を開ける[あなをあける]:to cause a loss|to make a hole (in)
（フミエ）こうして
まず 穴を開けるの
First of all, we open a hole like this.
No Data
見つかる[みつかる]:to be found/to be discovered, 大変[たいへん]:very|immense|serious||
サッチーに見つかったら
大変だけどね
But we'll be in big trouble if Satchii finds us...
サッチー？
Satchii?
サッチーも知らないの？
You don't even know who Satchii is?
赤い[あかい]:red|Red (i.e. communist), 大きい[おおきい]:big/large/great, 個[こ, コ]:counter for articles|counter for military units|individual, 個[か, カ]:counter for the ichi-ni-san counting system (usu. directly preceding the item being counted)/a noun read using its on-yomi
ほら 赤くて大きくて
４個ついてる
It's a big, red thing
with four things here...
ホント:truth/reality/actuality
ハァ… あんた
ホントに何も知らないのね
You really don't know anything.
引っ越す[ひっこす, ひきこす]:to move (house)/to change residence, ばかり:only/merely|approximately
（ヤサコ）今日 金沢(かなざわ)から
引っ越してきたばかりなの
I just got here from Kanazawa.
かしら:I wonder, かしら:head|hair (on one's head)
（フミエ）へえー
金沢にはサッチーいないのかしら？
Oh?
Maybe there are no Satchii in Kanazawa.
持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
（フミエ）ちょっと持ってて
Hold this for a sec.
電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 釣りざお[つりざお]:fishing rod, 屋[や]:(something) shop|somebody who sells (something) or works as (something)|somebody with a (certain) personality trait||, 売る[うる]:to sell
それは電脳釣りざお
メガシ屋で売ってるわ
It's a cyberfishing rod.
They sell it in Megasia.
ミッション:mission, 主役[しゅやく]:leading part/leading actor/leading actress
そして こいつが…
このミッションの主役よ
And now this...
The key player for this mission.
ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET
あなたのペット？
Your pet?
ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET, しもべ:servant/manservant/menial
ペットじゃないわ
私のしもべ オヤジよ
It's not a pet!
It's my servant. It's pretty old, so I call it Oyaji.
Oyaji also means old man
屋[や]:(something) shop|somebody who sells (something) or works as (something)|somebody with a (certain) personality trait||
（ヤサコ）これもメガシ屋で？
Is this also from Megasia?
売る[うる]:to sell
（フミエ）これは売ってないわ
They don't sell this.
丁寧[ていねい]:polite/courteous|careful
（ヤサコ）あっ これはご丁寧に
It's very polite.
Time to work, Oyaji!
仕事[しごと]:work/job|work
仕事だ オヤジ！
Restoration Complete
メタタグ:META tag, 貼る[はる]:to stick|to stretch|to form (e.g. ice on a pond)||
（フミエ）
さっ あとはメタタグを貼って
So next we slap a meta-tag on it.
壊れる[こわれる]:to be broken/to break|to fall through, にくい:hateful/abominable|amazing, にくい:difficult to .../hard to ...
これで
ちょっとは壊れにくくなるわ
And now it has increased protection.
よーし:alright/all right/right on
よーし 行け！　オヤジ
Get in there right now, Oyaji!
面白い[おもしろい]:interesting|amusing|pleasant
面白がってられないわよ
（ヤサコ）えっ？
This isn't a school trip, you know.
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, イリーガル:illegal, たとする:to appreciate/to be thankful
あんたが見た黒いのが
もしイリーガルだったとしたら
If the black thing you saw really was an Illegal,
嗅ぎつける[かぎつける]:to sniff out/to get wind of, やってくる:to come along/to come around|to arrive at the present
キュウちゃんが もうじき
嗅ぎつけてやってくるわ
the Kyuu-chans will hone in on it in no time.
イリーガル:illegal, 一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||
イリーガルって 一体…
What do you mean, Illegal?
It's a newly invented computer virus.
最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now, 発見[はっけん]:discovery/detection/finding, コンピューターウイルス:computer virus
最近 発見された
コンピューターウイルスよ
ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET, 感染[かんせん]:infection/contagion, ヤバい:dangerous|awful|terrific, らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
ペットに感染すると
ヤバいらしいわ
I heard that when it takes over a pet it can be dangerous.
（ヤサコ）どうなの？
Any luck?
うーん:hmm/well, 入り組む[いりくむ]:to be or become complicated
うーん…
思ったより入り組んでるわね
It's gone deeper than I thought.
様子[ようす]:state|appearance|sign
ちょっと 様子 聞いてみるわ
I'll try to ask how it's going.
もしもし:hello (e.g. on phone)|excuse me! (when calling out to someone), こちら:this way (direction close to the speaker or towards the speaker)/this direction|here (place close to the speaker or where the speaker is), 聞こえる[きこえる]:to be heard/to be audible|to be said to be
もしもし？　こちらフミエ
オヤジ 聞こえるか？
Hello, this is Fumie.
Can you hear me, Oyaji? Over.
オーバー:overcoat
オーバー？
応答[おうとう]:reply/answer/response
オヤジ オヤジ 応答せよ
Oyaji!
Oyaji, make some sound. Over.
オーバー:overcoat
オーバー？
応答[おうとう]:reply/answer/response
オヤジ オヤジ 応答せよ
Oyaji.
Oyaji, make a sound.
Well, how's it going?
ねえ どうなの？
It's bigger than I thought.
大きい[おおきい]:big/large/great
思ったより大きいわ
古い[ふるい]:old (not person)/aged/ancient, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 迷路[めいろ]:maze/labyrinth/blind alley, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
古い空間の中は
迷路みたいになってるの
Indeed, this obsolete Space is like a labyrinth.
もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 近く[ちかく]:near|nearly (e.g. "it took nearly one year")|shortly, ポイント:point, 見つかる[みつかる]:to be found/to be discovered
もっと近くに
ポイントが見つかればいいんだけど
I wish we could pinpoint them more easily...
マズい:unappetising|unskillful|ugly|
（フミエ）マズい！
Oh no!
Formatting
What's that?
なんなの？
（フミエ）キュウちゃんよ
It's a Kyuu-chan!
It usually takes them a lot longer!
もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, かかる:to span/to bridge/to cross, かかる:to take (a resource, e.g. time or money)|to hang
いつもなら
もっと時間かかるのに
What do we do?
予定[よてい]:plans/arrangement/schedule, 変更[へんこう]:change/modification/alteration
（ヤサコ）どうするの？
（フミエ）予定変更よ
Change of plans!
Don't tell me you want to abandon him!
まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected, 見捨てる[みすてる]:to abandon/to fail/to desert, 気[き]:spirit|nature|motivation||, 気[げ]:seeming/giving the appearance of/giving one the feeling of
まさか見捨てる気？
Those guys shoot at kuro bugs and pets without any distinction!
黒[くろ]:black|black go stone|guilt, ペット:pet, ペット:polyethylene terephthalate/PET, 見境[みさかい]:distinction/discrimination, 撃つ[うつ]:to shoot (at)|to attack/to defeat
あいつら 黒バグもペットも
見境なく撃ってくるのよ
一時[ひととき, いっとき]:moment|former times|two-hour period, 一時[いちじ]:one o'clock|once|for a time|, 撤退[てったい]:evacuation/withdrawal/revocation
ここは一時撤退しかないわ
（ヤサコ）そんな…
We have no choice but to withdraw for now!
But...!
Okay, let's go!
引き揚げる[ひきあげる]:to pull up|to increase|to withdraw||
さあ 引き揚げよ
（ヤサコ）ま… 待って！
Wait!
If we're shot, we're gonna be in big trouble!
私たち[わたしたち, わたくしたち]:we/us, 撃つ[うつ]:to shoot (at)|to attack/to defeat, 済む[すむ]:to finish|to merely result in something less severe than expected|to feel at ease|
私たちだって
撃たれたら ただじゃ済まないわ
Please... Please wait just a little longer!
お願い[おねがい]:request/wish|please
お願い ちょっとだけ…
ちょっとだけ待って
Densuke.
デンスケ？
What's wrong?
（フミエ）どうしたの？
What are you...?
何よ どうしたの？
What's up with you?
It's not here.
ここじゃない
Hey, what are you doing?
どういう:somehow/how/in what way
ねえ どういうことよ
（ヤサコ）違う！
Not here either.
Here!
近く[ちかく]:near|nearly (e.g. "it took nearly one year")|shortly, きっと:surely/undoubtedly|sternly
ここよ！
この近くにきっといるわ
I'm sure it's around here!
Hurry!
早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|
ねえ 早く！
Hurry up, Oyaji!
急ぐ[いそぐ]:to hurry/to rush/to hasten
（フミエ）オヤジ 急げ！
Hurry!
早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|
早く！
Here it comes!
来た！　くくっ…
来たわ！
Densuke!
デンスケ！
この！
Damn you!
Run for it!
逃げる[にげる]:to escape/to run away
逃げるわよ！
（ヤサコ）うん
今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently
（ヤサコ）こ… 今度は何？
What is it now?
In the end...
いよいよ:more and more/all the more|at last, お出まし[おでまし]:appearance/presence
いよいよ サッチーのお出ましだわ
Satchii has come, too!
What...
一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||, 街[がい]:.. street/.. quarter/.. district, 街[まち, ちょう]:town|street|109.09 m||
一体… 一体どうなってるの？
この街は
What on earth is going on in this town?!
Preview
Next episode
Dennou Coil
Coil Cyberinvestigation Agency
See you next time!
次回[じかい]:next time (occasion), 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, コイル:coil
（ヤサコ）
次回 「電脳コイル」
コイル:coil, 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 探偵[たんてい]:detective/sleuth/investigator, 局[きょく]:bureau|office (e.g. post, telephone)|affair|, 局[つぼね]:court lady|separate room in a palace (esp. for a lady) (Heian period)|room for a very low class prostitute|
〝コイル 電脳探偵局 〞
楽しみ[たのしみ]:enjoyment/pleasure|anticipation
お楽しみに